# Charles McEachern

☑ ch@rles.uno

• charles.uno

**J** (651) 269-9245

• Minneapolis, MN

# Summary

Ten years experience using Python for automation and analysis. Fluent in Linux and shell scripting. Recent emphasis on CI/CD infrastructure with Groovy, Jenkins, and Docker. Comfortable mentoring interns, onboarding employees, and creating educational materials for new technologies.

# Experience

Software Engineer, Cray Inc

2016-Present

- Built a CI/CD pipeline using Groovy, Docker, and shell scripts. Automatically compiled, tested, and distributed code on commit in support of 20 engineers and 50 repos.
- Interfaced with REST APIs for BitBucket and Jenkins using Python scripts. Automated triggers and cleanup to eliminate hours of error-prone browser menus.
- Implemented a **Python** module for control and testing of the Cray XC cooling system. Isolated bugs that, if released, would have cost millions of dollars in waste and damage.
- Mentored two interns, both of whom were awarded extensions. Prepared and presented educational materials to onboard dozens of new employees.

#### Performance Intern, Cray Inc

2014-2015

- Created a parallel Python harness to run nightly tests against Cray's performance analysis tools. Filed detailed bugs against Cray, Gnu, and Intel compilers.
- Automated **shell** environment configuration, **C++** and **Fortran** source code generation, and performance report parsing. Increased test code coverage dramatically.

## PhD Candidate, University of Minnesota

2009-2016

- Benchmarked and optimized a model of near-Earth electromagnetic waves in parallel Fortran. Analyzed hundreds of gigabytes of data in Python to identify novel patterns.
- Led laboratory exercises and tutored at-risk students individually. Communicated detailed concepts to audiences with varied technical backgrounds.
- Coordinated between professors, graduate teaching assistants, and undergraduate tutors as Head TA. Coached new team members to improve student outcomes.

### Education

## PhD, University of Minnesota

2009-2016

— Space physics, Burlaga/Arctowski Medal Fellow

### BA, St Olaf College

2005-2009

- Math (Distinction), Physics (Distinction), Magna Cum Laude